# **Kevin Le-Hsiu Cheng**

2245 Sheridan Road, Sargent Hall #207 Evanston, IL 60201

(312) 888-1113 kevincheng2018@u.northwestern.edu

- PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY -

Self-motivated individual who is passionate about gaining exposure in all the different facets of programming. Selftaught in Swift, HTML/CSS, and Javascript. Familiar with several OOP languages.

**Technical Skills:** Experience with C++, C#, Swift, Java, HTML/CSS, Javascript (jQuery, Node.js), MongoDB, Racket

Personal Website: kevincheng.tech

Relevant Coursework: Accelerated Linear Algebra and Multivariable Calculus, Fundamentals of Computer Programming, Data Structures and Management, Intro to Systems, Probability and Stochastic Processes

EDUCATION =

Northwestern University, Class of 2018

B.A. Computer Science and Economics

Intended Kellogg Managerial Analytics Certificate

Shanghai American School Puxi, Class of 2014

SAT Superscore: 2310 (CR: 780, M: 780, W: 750)

- EXPERIENCE -

Northwestern Associated Student Government Services Committee

Evanston, IL Oct 2015 - Present

UW GPA: 3.68

UW GPA: 3.83

iOS Developer

- Involved in improving the student experience at Northwestern University through the development of web and mobile applications
- Collaboratively learning the MEAN Stack to create an application that helps students at Northwestern University understand and plan the requirements and pre-requisites for their majors

A.T. Kearnev Shanghai, China Consultant Assistant Jul 2015 - Sep 2015

- Managed the Chinese-to-English translations of consulting slide-decks and interview notes by delegating and coordinating work to 9 part-time assistants
- Conducted industry benchmarking research for an innovation consulting case

## **Project Pitch Entrepreneurship Competition** Contestant

Evanston, IL Mar 2015 - May 2015

Collaborated in a small team to draft up an idea and create a mock-up for a start-up educational application, and then pitching the final idea to a panel of judges

# **Fullbridge Business Immersion Program**

Boston, MA

**Participant** 

Jul 2013 - Aug 2013

- Developed key business skills through the intensive 4-week business program
- Completed a final consulting project by running financial projections and merger analysis to create a business pitch for a mock board of directors

#### OTHER ORGANIZATIONS

Institute for Student Business Education, Technology Team Member 2015 - Present Chinese Student Association, Junior Executive 2015 - Present Northwestern University Boxing Club, A-Team Member 2014 - Present The Investment Club, Vice President 2011 - 2014

- Presented and educated members on investment concepts/strategies
- Created and designed the club website

## -ADDITIONAL INFORMATION-

**Hobbies:** Following the NBA, watching professional e-Sports, working out, playing with my pet dog Languages: Fluent in English and Chinese (Mandarin); proficient in Spanish